# **Julius Hietala**

## Fullstack Software Engineer



## Info

julius.hietala@gmail.com +358 44 561 0946 Helsinki, Finland / Remote

<u>LinkedIn ></u>

<u>Github ></u>

## **Working Languages**

Finnish

English

Swedish

### Bio

I have 4 years of experience as a Fullstack Software Engineer. For most of my career, I have been doing a lot of Node and React with TypeScript specifically, both at work and in side projects. These services have often been containerized and deployed to the cloud, usually to GCP, but I am no stranger to Kubernetes either where I have helped design multiple microservices. Rewriting and migrating legacy codebases into newer systems is something I enjoy a lot. I constantly keep an eye out for increasing development speed by applying modern build and CI/CD tools. I enjoy leading inter- and cross-team efforts, with an emphasis on supporting the learning of myself and others.

## Top skills

Programming Languages JavaScript, TypeScript, Python

Front End Development React, Next.js
Back End Development Node.is, Flask

Machine Learning / Data Science PyTorch, Numpy, Pandas

Databases SQL, PostgreSQL

Cloud Platforms GCP

Mobile Development Swift, React Native Dev Ops Kubernetes, CI/CD

## **Projects**

#### CTO, Founder | hanaa.io

2022 - present

Hanaa.io is a P2P platform for buying and selling used motorcycles. I have built the platform with the most modern web technologies and frameworks.

Tech: TypeScript, React, Python (flask), GraphQL, GCP

## Machine Learning Engineer | Voi Scooters

2022

I worked on an urgent project helping the company apply Machine Learning in their app.

Tech: iOS/Swift, Android/Java, CoreML, PyTorch

## Software Engineer, Founder | Stray Robots

2021 - 2022

I built tools and provided services for 2D and 3D computer vision ranging from labeling to custom CV algorithms.

Tech: Python, C++, PyTorch, Docker, ROS

## Work Experience

## Software Engineer | Nimble Robotics

2022 - present

Nimble is reimagining fulfillment with intelligent robots that can pick and pack anything.

Tech: Python

## Software Engineer | Smartly.io

2018 - 2022

I worked on the video template rendering engine and media library side of the product. Led multiple efforts of migrating legacy code into the new systems.

Tech: React, Redux, TypeScript, Node

## Solutions Engineer | Smartly.io

2017 - 2018

I helped some of the world's largest social media advertisers such as Airbnb and Uber in scaling their social media advertising by integrating them into the Smartly.io advertising platform.

Tech: JavaScript, Python

#### **Education**

Master of Science / Aalto University 2012-2022 Computer Science / Machine Learning, Data Science and Artificial Intelligence